<resources>
    <string name="Rotunda">The Rotunda at the University of Virginia was designed by Thomas Jefferson as the architectural and academic heart of his community of scholars, or what he termed the \"academical village.\" Jefferson modeled the Rotunda after the Pantheon in Rome, reducing the measurements so that the Rotunda would not dwarf the Pavilions. Construction began in 1822 and was completed in 1826 at a cost of almost $60,000. A fire, caused by faulty electrical wiring, started in the annex on October 27, 1895. In a dramatic attempt to save the Rotunda, engineering professor William H. Echols tried dynamiting the bridge between the annex and the Rotunda. Unfortunately, this blew a hole in the Rotunda, and the fire spread more rapidly. Before it could be brought under control, the annex, dome and interior of the Rotunda had been destroyed. Only the Rotunda\'s charred circular brick walls remained. Stanford White reconstructed the Rotunda adding his own designs in 1898. However, in 1973 Professor Frederick D. Nichols of the School of Architecture with the assistance of Francis L. Berkeley, Jr. supervised the restoration of the Rotunda to Jefferson\'s original design.</string>
    <string name="Chemistry">In 1961, the Board of Visitors at UVa hired Louis I. Kahn to design a new Chemistry Building opposite the McCormick Road dorms. Kahn decided to use reinforced concrete for the building rather than the usual brick design seen around grounds. His design featured a central structure rimmed with cylindrical towers, in a court framed by a larger building. The Chemistry Building evoked columns, but didn\’t sport any.</string>
    <string name="Clark_Hall">Clark Hall was completed in 1932 to hold the University of Virginia\'s School of Law. Its two-story, sky-lit, mural-decorated Memorial Library room \"is one of the Commonwealth\'s most significant 20th-century architectural interiors\". The building was listed on the National Register of Historic Places on September 5, 2008. Inside Clark Hall is the Charles L. Brown Science and Engineering Library.</string>
    <string name="OHill">Observatory Hill Dining Hall opened in 1974 and was orginially designed by Williams and Tazewell. Because of the limited capacity, in August 2005, the new OHill building was built next to the original one with $23.5 million cost. The new building offers 905 indoor seats and 204 outdoor terrace seats, a 20 percent increase in seating.</string>
    <string name="AFC_Clock">The University of Virginia Aquatic and Fitness Center opened during the summer of 1996. The 98,000 square-foot, $18.5 million complex features an Olympic-sized pool, warm-water pool, whirlpool and sauna, fitness areas and locker rooms, as well as classrooms, a dining area and a bookstore. The 50-meter pool features advanced lane lines and gutters, as well as a short course that ranges from seven to 14 feet in depth. The Aquatic and Fitness Center Phase II projected was completed in May of 2004. This project added a three-court gymnasium, an indoor running track, additional multipurpose rooms, a cycling room and expanded free weight and cardiovascular exercise areas.</string>
    <string name="Rice_Hall">Construction for Rice Hall began in April 2009 and was completed in November 2011. The building was designed by Bohlin Cywinski Jackson. The LEED certified, six-story building is located at the corner of Whitehead and Stadium roads behind Olsson Hall. With a gross area of approximately 100,000 square feet, building includes a courtyard, cyber-lounge, 150-seat auditorium, a Visualization Lab for Scientific Computing, a Computer Vision and Graphics Lab, facilities to support distance education, workrooms, study areas, conference rooms and flexible teaching and resource labs. The building itself serves as a \"living laboratory\" and public showcase for efficient operating systems where students, faculty and visitors alike can monitor the building\'s energy use. </string>
    <string name="Nau_Hall">Named for John L. Nau III (College \'68), president and CEO of Silver Eagle Distributors \- the nation\’s largest distributor of Anheuser Busch products and past president of the College Foundation, Nau Hall serves as the history building and houses classrooms, student lounges, computer labs, administrative offices, conference rooms and faculty and student meeting rooms. The only Starbucks on Grounds is located in Nau Hall. </string>
    <string name="Homer">This bronze statue, Blind Homer with his Student Guide, was given to the University in 1907 by John W. Simpson of New York City at the request of its sculptor, Richmond native Moses Ezekiel. It was unveiled in 1907 on the South end of the Lawn. The Lawn is used to refer either to the original grounds designed by Thomas Jefferson for the University of Virginia, or specifically to the grassy field around which the original university buildings are arrayed. The Lawn consists of four rows of colonnades on which alternate student rooms and larger buildings. The inner rank of colonnades, facing the central Lawn proper, contains ten Pavilions (which provided both classrooms and housing for professors) and 54 student rooms, while the outer rank, facing outward, contain six Hotels (typically service buildings and dining establishments) and another 54 student rooms. At the head of the colonnades, facing south down the Lawn, is the Rotunda, a one-half scale copy of the Pantheon in brick with white columns, that originally held the University\'s library. After the Rotunda fire, three academic buildings, Cocke Hall, Rouss Hall, and Cabell Hall (now Old Cabell Hall) were built at the base of the Lawn, enclosing the southern view which had previously been open to the Blue Ridge Mountains. </string>
    <string name="Chapel">In the late 19th century, community members raised funds to establish a non-denominational church on the University Grounds named the University Chapel. The Gothic Revival building was designed by Charles Emmet Cassell of Baltimore, the chapel\'s cornerstone was laid in 1885, and the chapel was dedicated in 1889. The chapel\'s carillon was a gift of the Seven Society. Nowadays, the University Chapel no longer holds regular religious services, but weddings and memorial services still take place inside. </string>



</resources>